Kathleen (Kate) Candon

kate.candon@yale.edu | kccandonk.github.io

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

I am interested in understanding how we can **create interactive agents that are more effectively able to help people.** My current research explores techniques to **leverage multimodal implicit feedback humans provide naturally** during interactions. In the future, I
want to explore how to use these techniques to better understand how and when agents should
ask for explicit feedback from humans during interactions. I am excited about creating situated
agents that can reason about and **adapt to the preferences of the humans they interact with, creating more positive experiences for users**.

EDUCATION -

2020 – Present Yale University

PhD in Computer Science

Advisors: Marynel Vázquez & Brian Scassellati

2012 – 2016 Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

B.S. in Mathematics with Computer Science GPA: 5.0/5.0, Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE -

2020 - Present

Interactive Machines Group & Social Robotics Lab at Yale University Graduate Student Researcher

- Researching prosocial behavior, implicit feedback, and explicit feedback in human-agent interactions
- Exploring situated agents and robotics applications in elder care settings to promote safe and independent aging in place
- Mentoring undergraduate students in various research activities

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS: PREPRINTS, UNDER REVIEW -

2022 **Candon, K.,** Hsu, Z., Chen, J., Kim, Y., Tsoi, N., & Vázquez, M. (2022).

Human Perceptions, Preferences, and Nonverbal Reactions to Prosocial Help

from an Interactive Agent. Under Review.

Tsoi, N., Candon, K., Milkessa, Y., & Vázquez, M. (2022). Bridging the Gap:

Unifying the Training and Evaluation of Neural Network Binary Classifiers.

arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.01367. *Under Review*.

PEER-REVIEWED WORKSHOP PAPERS -

2022 **Candon, K.,** & Vázquez, M. (2022). Context²: On the importance of the context of context in human robot interaction. *In HRI workshop on Context-*

Awareness in Human-Robot Interaction, 2022

| Α | W | ΙΑ | ١R | D | S |
|---|---|----|----|---|---|
|---|---|----|----|---|---|

2020, 2022 Honorable Mention for National Science Foundation Graduate Research

Fellowship

2022 CRA-WP Grad Cohort for Women: selected to attend conference for Women

in Computing

MENTORING -

| 2022- | Helen Zhou (Undergraduate Researcher, Interactive Machines Group) |
|-----------|--|
| 2022- | Ariel Melendez (Undergraduate Researcher, Social Robotics Lab) |
| 2021-2022 | Jesse Chen (Undergraduate Researcher, Interactive Machines Group) |
| 2021 | Yoony Kim (Undergraduate Researcher, Interactive Machines Group) |
| 2021 | Zoe Hsu (STARS Undergraduate Researcher, Interactive Machines Group) |

TEACHING EXPERIENCE -

Spring 2022 Artificial Intelligence, Yale University

Teaching Fellow

Fall 2021 Intelligent Robotics, Yale University

Teaching Fellow

Fall 2015 Fundamentals of Programming, MIT

Lab Assistant

Winter 2014 Global Teaching Labs at MIT

Teaching Ambassador in Pavia, Italy

 Planned and taught month of math and computer science classes to high school students

WORK EXPERIENCE ———

2018-2020 Massachusetts Executive Office of Health and Human Services (EOHHS)
Senior Strategy Manager, MassHealth

- Lead Covid-19 projects including: scheduling bi-weekly safety audits of almost 400 nursing facilities, developing and funding infection protocols for inpatient psychiatric facilities
- Conducted research and analyses to refine strategic direction of integrated care programs for dual eligible members in Massachusetts as part of ongoing negotiations with the Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services
- Researched eligibility policies and processes to identify opportunities for improvement
- Managed primary care initiatives across 6+ agencies as part of EOHHS effort to create a behavioral health ambulatory treatment system
- Collaborated with academic research teams analyzing Medicaid data to provide programmatic input
- Managed a Strategy Analyst who was promoted to Strategy Manager after one year

2016-2018 McKinsey & Company

Business Analyst

- Researched and communicated solutions for clients on strategic and analytical projects across industries including financial services, retail, transportation, and the public sector
- Investigated customer experience in the public sector through descriptive and multivariate analysis of survey with 15,000+ respondents, contributing to McKinsey article "Understanding the customer experience with government"
- Overhauled sourcing process, built SQL database, and structured businessas-usual analyses for major U.S. fashion retailer

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT -

2017-2020 **Back on My Feet**

Volunteer with Boston, MA & Washington, DC chapters

 Supported members in their transition from homelessness to independence through weekly runs

2016-2018 McKinsey Social Impact Group

Member of pro-bono teams

- Researched profiles of successful, scalable businesses in rural communities in support of the Center on Rural Innovation
- Conducted market research on potential donors and giving organizations in the DC area for Back on My Feet

2016 Codelt at MIT

Volunteer Mentor

 Mentored students in MIT's student-run weekly programming class for middle school girls